<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows on Scott Guymer</title><link>https://www.scottguymer.co.uk/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in windows on Scott Guymer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 07:54:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.scottguymer.co.uk/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up Git with SSH on Windows with PowerShell</title><link>https://www.scottguymer.co.uk/post/setting-up-git-with-ssh-on-windows-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 07:54:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.scottguymer.co.uk/post/setting-up-git-with-ssh-on-windows-with-powershell/</guid><description>When you activate 2FA on your GitHub account using HTTPS becomes a little more difficult because you can&amp;rsquo;t simply use your password anymore.
The simple solution is to use a PAT token as your password when prompted from the command line.
But managing these tokens can be a bit of pain.
You can also clone using SSH. For our Mac and Linux friends, we know it&amp;rsquo;s easy, it should be on windows, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t yet&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Docker as a build system - with Windows containers</title><link>https://www.scottguymer.co.uk/post/docker-as-a-build-system-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 09:01:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.scottguymer.co.uk/post/docker-as-a-build-system-windows/</guid><description>Whilst I am familiar with linux containers I havent had the chance to use windows containers much so this is part of a series where I explore the features and differences of windows container. These posts are written for someone who is fairly new to the docker experience.
Docker doesnt just have to be used just to build, package and deploy applications. Its ability to provide an isolated environment that you have control over is great for build systems in general.</description></item></channel></rss>